Amanda Zapata

Orlando, FL • +1 407-844-3730 • amandazapata802@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/zapamanda

Technical Writer

With my experience, I believe that my acquired skills will easily transfer into a new career in technical writing. Over the past three years of my career, I have honed my skills in developing and implementing engaging learning strategies, copyediting, and maintaining positive relationships with people, as well as tracking and reporting on progress.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Osceola County District Schools • Saint Cloud, FL, USA • 08/2021 - 05/2023 9th Grade English Teacher

- Increased reading proficiency skills in students from 48% to over 70% in 5 months by deliberately practicing and mastering test-taking strategies.
- Achieved higher writing test scores among students by 74% in 4 months by proofreading essays and facilitating writing workshops.
- Provided detailed written communication by messaging parents about grade reports.
- Prioritized storytelling and analyzing texts to bring life to novels read in class to promote critical thinking about difficult concepts.
- Assisted navigating educational technology in the classroom such as Office 365 products to promote problem-solving skills by easily editing and revising essays.

Liberty Middle School • Chickasaw, FL, USA • 01/2021 - 05/2021 **Student Teacher**

- Motivated students to independently complete reading and writing tasks.
- Managed multiple projects such as creating creative and engaging detailed lesson plans while still meeting University assignment deadlines.
- Provided simultaneous supervision in a fast-paced environment to both in-person and online students in a hybrid setting by establishing integration of Zoom and Microsoft Teams.
- Collaboratively worked with the department to create detail-oriented activities for students to remain enthusiastic and engaged while studying literature pieces.

Siemens Energy • Orlando, FL, USA • 05/2018 - 07/2018 Summer Intern

- Collaboration among on-site managers and other student interns on various company projects and programs on Wind Turbine operations.
- Wrote internal documentation and blog posts about the internship experience that reached multiple audiences within the company.
- Applied instructional design and journalism to create company flyers, brochures, and postcards advocating for S.T.E.A.M. education in local public schools.
- Worked independently to organize data using Microsoft Excel, Lotus Notes, and the company's internal software.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Secondary Education In English Language Arts

University Of Central Florida

SKILLS

Comprehensive, Cultural Competence, Reading Skill, Communication, Leadership, Research, Process Documentation, Microsoft Office, Understanding Cultural Differences, Educational Planning, Learning Environment, Project Management, Blended Learning, Lesson Planning, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Teams, Data Analysis, Microsoft PowerPoint, Teaching